“谢谢你”
随想
Random thoughts
2004年情人节
for Valentine's Day, 2004.
今天是卡片公司发明的节日
Today is a holiday invented by greeting card companies...
故意让人伤心难过
to make people feel like crap.
我今天跷了班
I ditched work today.
搭火车去蒙托克
Took a train out to Montauk
不知道为什么
I don't know why.
我平常不会这么冲动
I'm not an impulsive person.
可能是早上起床心情欠佳
I guess I just woke up in a funk this morning.
我要把车修好
I need to get my car fixed.
辛蒂，我是乔尔
Hi, Cindy. It's Joel. Joel!
乔尔啦
我今天不舒服
I don't feel very well today.
应该不是食物中毒
no, food poisoning, I think
这里的海滩冷死人了
It's goddamn freezing on this beach.
二月的蒙托克美极了
Montauk in February - brilliant, Joel.
有几页撕掉了
Pages ripped out. Don't remember doing that.
不记得有这回事
我两年没写日记了
It appears this is my first entry in two years.
说沙子太言重
Sand is overrated.
只是小石头而已
It's just tiny little rocks.
真希望我能结交新欢
If only I could meet someone new.
只是把到妹的机会渺茫
I guess my chances of that happening are somewhat diminished...
因为我无法正眼看陌生女子
since I'm incapable of making eye contact
with a woman I don't know.
或许我该回头找娜欧蜜
Maybe I should get back together with naomi.
她是个好女孩
She was nice.
好就够了
nice is good.
她爱我
She loved me.
我怎么会见一个爱一个？
Why do I fall in love with every woman I see...
对我没兴趣的我也爱？
who shows me the least bit of interest?
“蒙托克”
你好
Hi.
你说什么？
I'm sorry?
我在向你问好
I just said hi.
你好
Hi, hello.
可以坐近一点吗？
Okay if I sit closer?
你要去多远？
How far are you going?
洛维尔常青社
Rockville Center.
不会吧，跟我一样
Me, too.
真的吗？
Really?
有多少人能殊途同归？
What are the odds?
你很面熟耶
Do I know you?
有没有在诚品买过书？
Do you ever shop at Barnes and noble?
有啊
Sure.
那就对了
That's it! I've seen you.
怎样？
我见过你
我在那里当过…
Book slave there for five years now.
五年的廉价劳工
天哪
I would have thought I would remember you.
结果我认不出你 五年了吗？
可能是头发吧
It might be the hair.
怎样？
What might?
变得了很多
It changes a lot. The color.
发色吧，难怪你认不出我
That's why you might not recognize me.
这是颓废蓝
It's called Blue Ruin.
这样啊
The color.
名字很炫吧？
Snappy name, huh?
我喜欢 是啊
I like it.
这家公司生产了
This company makes a whole line of colors with snappy names.
各种名字很炫的颜色
血腥红、狂热黄、革命绿
Red Menace, Yellow Fever, Green Revolution...
有人专门在想这些名字
That would be a job, coming up with those names.
有那种工作吗？
You think there could possibly be a job like that?
能有几种发色？
How many hair colors could there be?
五十种？
Fifty?
有人专做这种事
Someone's got that job.
橘子特务
Agent Orange.
我自己取的名字
I came up with that one.
融入了我多变的个性
I apply my personality in a paste.
我倒不以为然
I doubt that very much.
你不了解我
Well, you don't know me, so
所以你不会知道的
you don't know, do you?
抱歉，我只是…
I'm sorry.
我只是礼貌性回答
I was just trying to be nice.
我懂了
I got it.
对了，我叫克蕾婷（小柑橘）
My name's Clementine, by the way.
我叫乔尔
I'm Joel.
嗨，乔尔
Hi, Joel.
你好
no jokes about my name.
别取笑我的名字
应该不会啦，你很有礼貌
Oh no. You wouldn't do that.
You're trying to be nice.
我不觉得你的名字好笑
I don't know any jokes about your name.
卡通主题曲
Huckleberry Hound.
我不懂你的意思
I don't know what that means.
卡通啊
Huckleberry Hound?
你脑筋秀逗啊？
What are you, nuts?
你有说过
It's been suggested.
“亲爱的…亲爱的克蕾婷”
Oh, my darling, oh, my darling, oh, my darling Clementine...
“你消声匿迹了”
You are lost and gone forever, dreadful sorry, Clementine.
“我很遗憾，克蕾婷”
没听过吗？
抱歉，只不过…
Sorry. It's a pretty name, though. Really nice.
这个名字很好听
意思是“仁慈”吧？
It means merciful, right?
仁慈宽厚？
Clemency?
可惜名不副实
Although it hardly fits.
我是有仇必报的女人
I'm a vindictive little bitch, truth be told.
天哪，看不出来耶
I wouldn't think that about you.
你怎么可能看出来嘛
Why wouldn't you?
不知道，就是…
I don't know.
你看起来人很好
You seemed nice.
我人很好？
now I'm nice?
天哪，你没别的形容词了吗？
Don't you know any other adjectives?
我不想当好人
I don't need to be nice.
没这必要，别人也不必对我好
And I don't need anybody to be nice to me.
好吧
Okay.
乔尔？
Joel?
你叫乔尔，对吧？
It's Joel, right?
对
Yes.
很抱歉刚才对你大小声
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
我今天心情不好
I'm a little of out sorts today.
我要承认一件糗事
My embarrassing admission is I really like that you're nice right now.
我喜欢你人很好
现在…
不知道下一刻我会怎么想
I can't tell from one moment to the next
what I'm going to like, but...
但现在…
right now I'm glad you are.
很庆幸你人很好
我有点事…
I have some stuff that I probably should...
可能要…
我正在写…
Oh! I'm sorry.
对不起
Okay. no...
没关系
Sure. That's okay.
没事，我无所谓啦
这碰巧是…
好吧
你保重
Take care, then.
天哪
Jesus.
嗨!
我可以顺道载你一程
Hi. I could give you a ride if you need.
好冷
It's cold.
对，冷死人了 好吧，快上车
Yeah! Okay.
It is frosty.
你没在跟踪我吧？
You're not a stalker or anything, right?
我没有
I'm not a stalker.
是你先找我搭讪的，记得吗？
You're the one that talked to me, remember?
这是歹徒老掉牙的把戏了
That is the oldest trick in the stalker book
是吗？
Really? There's a stalker book?
歹徒还有把戏？
好极了
我倒想研究一下
I've got to read that one.
很抱歉我疯疯癫癫的
I'm sorry if I came off sort of nutso.
我平常不会这样
I'm not really.
没关系
That's okay. I didn't think you were.
我不觉得你疯疯癫癫
要不要喝一杯？
Do you want to have a drink?
我有很多酒可以…
I have lots of drinks, and I could --
算了
never mind. That was stupid.
抱歉，是我胡说八道
I'm embarrassed now. Goodnight.
我觉得好丢脸
不会啦
晚安
两杯颓废蓝
Two Blue Ruins.
谢谢
Thank you.
干杯吧，年轻人
Drink up, young man.
这样勾引你比较自然
It'll make the whole seduction part less repugnant.
开玩笑啦
I'm just kidding! Come on.
拜托
你很沉默寡言
You're kind of closed-mouthed, aren't you?
抱歉，我…
I'm sorry.
我的生活…
You know, my life isn't that interesting.
乏善可陈
每天就是上班和回家
I go to work, I come home...
没什么话好说
I don't know what to say.
你应该看看我的日记
You should read my journal.
里面几乎是…
It's just... blank
一片空白
Really?
是吗？
Does that make you sad or anxious?
你觉得伤心或焦虑？
我经常焦虑，觉得生活不够充实
I'm always anxious, thinking I'm not living my life to the fullest.
要抱握每个机会
Taking advantage of every possibility and...
确定分秒都没浪费
making sure I'm not wasting one second of the little time I have.
我有想过
I think about that.
是吗？
你真的人很好
You're really nice.
天哪，我不能再说这句话了
I have to stop saying that.
我要嫁给你
I'm gonna marry you.
我认定了
I know it.
好啊
Okay.
乔尔，改天陪我去查理士河
Joel. You should come up to the Charles with me sometime.
这个季节都结冰了
It gets frozen this time of year.
好像很可怕
That sounds scary.
对啊
Fxactly.
我会准备点心
I'll pack a picnic - a night picnic
晚上野餐
晚上野餐感觉不一样
- night picnics are different.
我们可以…
That sounds good.
好主意
但我该走了
But I should go now.
留下来嘛
You should stay.
不行，我真的…
I really have to get up so early and...
我明天要早起
我希望你打电话给我
I would like you to call me.
可以吗？
Would you do that?
我很期待
I'd like it.
好
Yes.
打电话来祝我情人节快乐
Wish me a happy Valentine's Day when you call.
我会很感动的
That'd be nice.
你怎么现在才打？
What took you so long?
我刚进门
I just walked in.
你想我吗？
You miss me?
很奇怪，我好想你
Oddly enough, I do.
你说你想我
You said I do.
我们算是结婚了
I guess that means we're married.
大概吧
I guess so.
明晚？去冰上渡蜜月？
Tomorrow night?
这个季节冰层很厚
Honeymoon on Ice?
It's really solid this time of year.
我不知道…
I don't know...
过来嘛
Come on...
快点…
好美
It's so beautiful.
可不是吗？
Isn't it?
别跑太远
Don't go too far!
还好吧？
Are you okay?
我的屁股!
Oh, my ass!
我该回去了
I think I should go back
来嘛
Come on!
若冰层破掉怎么办？
But what if it breaks?
怎么办？你真的在乎吗？
What if?. Do you really care right now?
过来一下
Come here, please.
滑啊…
Slidey-slidey, slidey-slidey.
不错嘛
This looks good.
过来，让你体验一下
Let me show you this one thing.
你要干嘛？
What are you doing?
来啊
Come on.
好像有冰裂掉的声音
Think I heard a crack
不会裂开
It's not going to crack
也不会破掉，很厚的
Or break It's so thick
说说你认识哪些星座
Show me which constellations you know.
不知道
I don't know.
我不太懂
I don't know any.
知道的就告诉我
Show me which ones you know.
好吧
Okay.
Oh! There's Osidius.
那是奥西迪斯
哪里？
Where?
在那里，有没有看到？
Right there. See?
弧线和十字架
A sort of a swoop and a cross.
奥西迪斯星座
Osidius the Fmphatic.
你唬烂的啦
You're full of shit, right?
才没有，那是奥西迪斯
no. Osidius right there.
弧线和十字架
Swoop and a cross.
别闹了
Shut up!
克蕾婷…
天亮了
很抱歉叫醒了你
Sorry to wake you, but we're here.
我们到了
我能不能去你家？
Can I come over to your house...
睡觉？
to sleep? I'm so tired.
我好累
好
Okay.
好啊
Sure.
我去拿牙刷
Let me get my toothbrush.
好
你先…
什么事？
Yes?
需要我帮忙吗？
Can I help you?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
要我帮你什么忙吗？
Can I help you with something?
不用啊
no.
你怎么会在这里？
What are you doing here?
你干嘛这样问？
I'm not really sure what you're asking me.
Oh.
谢谢
Thanks.
【美丽心灵的永恒阳光】
我们要找159
那是什么号码？
我不知道那是什么号码，天哪
我以为号码会亮灯 至少要标明…
Is that him?
是他吗？
I think so.
应该是
对，就是他
Yeah, that's him.
等一下，就是他
乔尔
Hey, Joel.
法兰克
Frank
干!
Shit.
天哪
The only Valentine's Day cards I get are from my mother.
我唯一收到的情人卡是我妈寄的
太可悲了
How pathetic is that?
你有克蕾婷真幸运，她是好女孩
You're lucky you have Clementine.
She is way cool.
有计划好要和她共度情人节吗？
You got any big Valentine's Day plans with her?
“忘情诊所”
没有
no.
只剩一天了，快去订位吧
It's only a day away.
Better make some reservations or something.
Don't want to end up at Mickey D's, right?
别沦落到去麦当劳过节 速食店恋曲
McRomance!
要不要点薯条配奶昔？
You want some fries with that shake?
我要去睡觉了
I have to go to sleep now, Frank
才八点半耶
It's 8:30.
派屈克，别再唱了
Patrick, stop it.
好吧
Okay.
阿波罗剧院有好戏上场了
Showtime at the Apollo.
小声一点
Quiet.
好啦
快拿下来
Get it off your head.
乔尔，你好啊
Hey, Joel. What's up?
法兰克
Hi, Frank
我只收到我妈寄的情人卡
I only get Valentine's Day cards from my mom.
太可悲了
How pathetic is that?
你有克蕾婷真幸运
You're lucky you have Clementine.
有计划好要和她共度情人节吗？
You got any big Valentine's Day plans with her?
没有
no.
只剩一天了
It's only a day away.
快去订位吧
Better make a reservation somewhere.
别沦落到去麦当劳过节
Don't want to end up at Mickey D's.
不会吧
Oh, no.
对，再过三天就是情人节了
Yes.
Valentine's Day is three days away.
要快点搞定
I want it resolved.
我要采取主动
I'm willing to be the one to resolve it.
我打电话给她
So I call her, and she's changed her number.
她换电话了
我去精品店想买礼物
So I walked over to Antic Attic to get her something.
想送给她
I thought I'd go over to work, give her an early Valentine...
我想去公司
提早祝她情人节快乐
and you won't believe it?
你们绝对不会相信
她和一个年轻男人在一起
She's there...
with this guy, this really young guy.
她看着我，好像不认识我
And she looks at me like she doesn't even know who I am.
抱歉
Fxcuse me?
你要找什么吗？
an I help you find something, sir?
克蕾婷宝贝
Hey, Clem-ato.
派屈克宝贝
Patrick! Baby boy!
你怎么来了？
我想让你惊喜一下
What are you doing here, baby?
需要什么再告诉我吧
Just came to surprise you.
Let me know if you need something.
你好吗？
How are you?
不错，很无聊，很累
Pretty good, pretty bored, pretty tired.
我想剥光你的衣服 好啊
I so want what's in your suit.
Oh, good.
她凭什么那样对我？
Why would she do that to me?
谁想吸一口？
Does anybody want a joint?
罗伯，拜托你别闹了
Rob, give it a rest.
天哪，她在惩罚我
She's punishing me.
我知道
For being honest..
惩罚我的诚实
太过份了
I should just go to her house.
我应该去她家找她
no. You don't want to go there.
不行，千万别去
千万别去，走开啦
实在是太…
Get off me. It's too...
对
Right.
是啊
I don't want to seem desperate.
我不想把事情闹大
就当作是一次教训吧
Joel, why don't you just see this as a sign?
好聚好散
Make a clean break
乔尔…
Alright, seriously, here's the deal.
说正经的…
罗伯…
就这么办吧
Don't do that.
别闹了，罗伯，你想干嘛？
Rob, what are you doing?
你有何高见，凯莉？
What's your fucking suggestion?!
你有什么妙点子？
What's your brilliant, reasoned solution?
你又想牵托到我们吗？
You're going to make this about our shit now?
这件事与我们无关
This isn't about us.
对，与我们无关，这是乔尔的事
I agree. It's not about us.
他成年了
It's about Joel, who's an adult.
不是凯莉妈妈的儿子
not Mama Carrie's kid.
你去洗衣服啦
Why don't you go do your laundry!
好极了
That's great. That's good.
很好
好吧
Okay.
拉金伉俪:克蕾婷
把乔尔贝里许从记忆中消除了
请别再向她提起两人的关系
忘情诊所向二位致谢
What is it?! I don't know.
这是什么？ 不知道，这家诊所…
It's some place that does a thing...
能让人… “忘情诊所”
早安，忘情诊所
Good morning. Lacuna.
抱歉，该方案只到…
no, I'm sorry.
That offer expired after the new Year.
元旦过后
对，我们可以替你安排…
Sure.
We can fit you in... how about on the 5th?
五号可以吗？
星期三
That's a Wednesday.
好的，请问贵姓大名？
Great. Could you spell that, please?
好，请留下白天的联络电话
Okay. And we'll need a daytime phone number.
好极了
Great. Have a nice day. See you then.
日安，到时候见
有何贵干？
May I help you?
我是乔尔贝里许
I'm Joel Barish.
你说什么？
Fxcuse me?
我是乔尔贝里许
I'm Joel Barish.
我和医生约好了，他姓…
I have an appointment with doctor...
莫兹维
Mierzwiak Here.
来吧，请你先填资料
Could you please fill this out?
我只是想找他谈谈
I just want to talk to him.
还是要请你先填资料
You still need to fill the form out.
是吗？
Really?
谢谢你
Thank you.
我没有笔
I don't have a pen.
那里有支笔
There's a pen right there.
早安，忘情诊所
Good morning. Lacuna.
对，该方案结束了
Oh, that offer expired after the new Year.
只到元旦过后
贝里许先生？
Mister Barish?
今天好吗？
How are we today?
不太好
not too good, actually.
天哪!史丹!
Oh my God! Stan!
抱歉，我只是…
Sorry. I was just
我在上班耶
I'm working.
对不起
给你，医生
Here, Doctor.
谢谢你，不应该让你看到的
Thank you.
You should not have seen this.
抱歉
I apologize.
这是唬人的吧？这是克蕾婷的…
This is a hoax, right?
如假包换
I mean, this is Clem's
没错
I assure you, no.
这是不可能的事
There's no such thing as this.
我们的资料都要保密
Our files are confidential, so I can't show you evidence.
所以不能拿证据给你看
我只能说…
Suffice it to say that Miss Kruczynski was not happy...
库钦斯基小姐过得不快乐
她想抛弃过去
and she wanted to move on.
我们只是如她所愿
We provide that possibility.
库钦斯基小姐过得不快乐
...was not happy, and wanted to move on.
她想抛弃过往
我们只是如她所愿
We provide that possibility.
这是什么鬼话？
What the hell is that?
她没遇过比我好的男人
I'm the nicest guy she ever went out with.
干!
Ah, fuck!
罗伯，别闹了
Rob, give it a rest!
没关系
It's okay.
凯莉，我在做鸟舍
I am making a birdhouse.
我无言以对
Joel, you know Clementine's just like that.
克蕾婷就是那么善变
她做事很冲动
So impulsive.
一时兴起就想忘记你
She decided to erase you as a lark
一时兴起？
A lark?
你凭什么这样对我？ 不行，等一下…
Why did you do that?
对不起 医生在吗？
Wait, wait!
医生，他硬要闯进来
I want it done. now.
好，替我做吧
现在就做
I told him pre-Valentine's Day is our busy time -
我说过情人节之前是我们的旺季
没关系，玛丽
That's okay, Mary.
可是还有别人在等
But there are people waiting.
贝里许先生，请进吧
Mister Barish, if you'd like to come inside.
玛丽，请你接待吴太太
Mary, if you'd take care of Mrs. Woo.
好的
吴太太，再见
Goodbye, Mrs. Woo. Of course.
贝里许先生… 首先你要回家
The first thing we need you to do, Mister Barish...
is to go home and collect everything you own that has...
整理出和克蕾婷有关的东西
some association with Clementine.
一样都不能少
Anything.
我们就用那些东西
We'll use these items...
在你大脑中创造克蕾婷的蓝图
to create a map of Clementine in your brain.
我们需要…
We'll need photos, clothing...
照片
衣服、礼物
gifts, books she may have bought you...
她送你的书
你们一起买的CD
CD's you may have bought together, journal entries...
日记
我们要搬空你家
消除你对克蕾婷的记忆
We want to empty your home...
We want to empty your life of Clementine.
等到蓝图绘制好之后
After the mapping is done,
专家今晚会去府上替你消除记忆
our technicians will do the erasing in your home tonight.
你明天早上醒来以后
That way, when you awake in the morning,
躺在床上
you'll find yourself in your...
感觉什么事都没发生过
own bed, as if nothing has happened, a new life awaiting you.
崭新的人生在等着你
没长眼睛啊!
Wake up, buddy!
抱歉，索波太太
I'm sorry, Mrs. Sobel.
同一个月不能消除记忆三次
You can't have the procedure done three times in one month.
就是违反规定啊
It's just not our policy here.
你今天好吗，贝里许先生？
How are you today, Mister Barish?
我还在
我知道情况紧急，我们尽力而为
I know it's an emergency.
先帮你预约三月一日
We'll do everything we can.
We can fit you in on March 1st.
你找医生谈谈
Maybe you could talk to the Doctor.
好，那就约个时间吧
What day would you like to come in this week?
你这礼拜哪天方便？
贝里许先生!
Mister Barish!
他今天下午很忙
明天12点15分左右可以吗？
我们二月最忙，因为情人节
February is very busy for us because of Valentine's Day.
他是史丹芬克
This is Stan Fink,
我们最资深、技术最好的专家
one of our most experienced and skilled technicians.
今晚就由他为你服务
He'll be handling your case tonight.
幸会，贝里许先生
Great to meet you, Mister Barish.
我叫乔尔贝里许
My name is Joel Barish...
要消除对克蕾婷的记忆
and I'm here to erase Clementine Kruczynski.
很好
Very good. now tell me about Clementine.
告诉我有关…
…克蕾婷的事
我两年前和一个
I was living with this woman, naomi...
名叫娜欧蜜的女人 …同居
a couple years ago, and my friends, Rob and Carrie...
我朋友罗伯和凯莉
邀我们去参加海滩派对
invited us to this party at the beach.
我不喜欢派对
I don't like parties.
娜欧蜜不能去
And naomi couldn't go, but I went...
但我去了
我认识了克蕾婷
and I met Clementine.
对不起
I'm sorry.
先从你最近的记忆开始
We'll start with your most recent memories,
然后往前回溯
and work backwards from there.
每段记忆都有情绪核心
There's an emotional core to each of our memories...
一旦根除了核心
and when you eradicate that core, it starts its degradation process.
记忆就会开始退化
等到你明天早上醒来
By the time you wake up in the morning,
目标的记忆就会荡然无存了
all the memories we've targeted...
will have withered and disappeared.
一切都如梦初醒
As in a dream upon waking.
会不会损坏大脑？
Is there any risk of brain damage?
技术上消除记忆就是损坏大脑
Technically speaking, the procedure is brain damage.
只是和一夜宿醉差不多
But it's on a par with a night of heavy drinking.
没什么后遗症
nothing you'll miss.
舒服吗？
Comfortable?
我们要绘制…
What we're doing here is actually creating a map of your brain.
你的大脑蓝图
好，开始吧
Let's get started.
今晚要处理好就得赶工
If we want to get this procedure underway tonight,
看到每样东西都要有所回应
we have some work to do.
I want you to react to these objects.
请你配合
那个东西有个故事…
There's a good story behind that
不，只要有情绪反应就够了
I'll get a much better emotional read-out...
最好避免口头上的描述
if you refrain from any sort of verbal description of the items.
请你专心地回忆
Just please try to focus on the memories.
抱歉，我懂了
Sorry.
大脑活动正常
Healthy activity up there again.
很好
Healthy read-outs.
指数正常
Very good.
很好
再换一样东西
Here's another object.
下一件物品
next item.
好，蛋头先生
Po-ta-to head.
下一件物品
next item.
好，蛋头先生
请你专心地回忆
Just focus on the memories.
派屈克，帮个忙
Patrick, do me a favor, will you?
派屈克，请你帮个忙
好
Can you check the voltage regulator?
把电压调强一点
怎么回事？
Voltage looks fine.
电压很正常
Really?
是吗？
I'm not wiping as clean as I like here.
记忆消除得不够干净
技术上消除记忆就是损坏大脑
Technically, the procedure is brain damage.
只是和一夜宿醉差不多 没什么后遗症
But it's on a par with a night of heavy drinking.
检查连线是否正常
Check the connections, please.
原来你在这儿
There you are.
怎么回事？
我都搞糊涂了
I don't understand what I'm looking at.
我怎么会站在这里？
Why am I standing here and...
天哪，似曾相识
Oh, my God, deja vu.
似曾相识
This is so... We should get started.
我觉得…
好，开始吧
If we want to get the procedure...
今晚要处理好就得赶工了
underway tonight, we have some work to do.
我进入大脑里了
I'm in my head already, aren't I?
大概吧
I suppose so.
这样可以了
差不多就是这样了
This is what it would look like.
很好
Very good.
记忆消除之后我们会销毁纪念品
We'll dispose of these mementos when we're done here.
免得你日后在家里
Then you won't be confused later
对这些东西感到莫名其妙
by their unexplainable presence in your home.
开始吧…派屈克？
Patrick?
什么事？
派屈克？
Patrick?
Why are there so many wires?
这么多条线是干嘛？
因为设备很多啊
Because we have a lot of equipment.
有用吗？
Does that help?
你确定机器操作正确吗？
Are you sure you set that thing up properly?
怎样？
贝里许先生，你今天好吗？
好了，贝里许先生
这样好多了
I don't know if I like this.
贝里许先生？
我不确定这样做妥不妥当
试试看再说，快完成了
你的日记，那是无价之宝
Ah, yourjournal.
That'll be invaluable.
我今晚认识了一个人
I met someone tonight. I don't know what to do.
我今晚认识了一个人，天哪
我不知道该怎么办才好
Her name's Clementine and she's amazing.
她叫克蕾婷
她是个特别的女孩
我不知道… 她叫克蕾…
天哪
Whoa, Jesus! What? What?
怎么了…
Careful! Step back!
拜托!小心! 怎么了？
走开!
慢慢来
没事了
It's fine.
千万别毁了他的大脑
Let's not roach the guy.
好，消除了
Alright. We got that one.
你不觉得这里像猪圈吗？
This place is sort of a dump, don't you think?
这是公寓，派屈克
It's an apartment, Patrick
派屈克
Patrick
不是猪圈
Well, not a dump, but sort of plain.
但有点简陋
平凡无奇
Uninspired.
而且有股…臭味
And there's sort of a stale smell.
派屈克…
Patrick Can we just get through this?
先把正事办完，今晚还得赶工呢
We've got a long night ahead of us.
好吧
猪头
这是我最后一次见到你
This is the last time I saw you.
现在是三点钟
It's three o'clock
我把你的车撞坏了
I kind of wrecked your car.
酒后驾车
Driving drunk
你真该死
It's pathetic.
我只是微醺而已
I was a little tipsy.
别骂我该死
Don't call me pathetic!
你很该死
It is pathetic.
做事不负责任，可能会撞死人
It's irresponsible.
You could have killed somebody.
不知道，你可能真的撞死人了
Maybe you did kill somebody.
要不要看看电视新闻？
Should we turn on the news and see?
还是要检查保险杆
Should I check the grill to see if there's children or small animals?
别闹了，我没撞死人
有没有小孩或小动物？
It's just a fucking dent.
只是撞凹了
天哪，你像个老太婆碎碎念的
You're like an old lady or something.
你是怎样？
What are you like?
酒鬼吗？
A wino?
酒鬼？
Jesus.
天哪
Are you from the 50's or something?
你是50年代的人吗？酒鬼？
A wino?
面对现实吧
Face it.
你是气我晚归，丢下你一个人
You're freaked out because I was out late without you...
你那个猪脑袋只想着
and in your little, wormy brain, you're trying to figure out...
我到底有没有跟别人上床
Did she fuck someone tonight?
我早就料到你会跟别人上床
See, Clem, I assume you fucked someone tonight.
你不是习惯这样勾引人？
Isn't that how you get people to like you?
对不起
I'm sorry, okay?
我不是故意的克蕾婷…
I didn't mean it.
钥匙还你
Your keys.
我只是…
I won't need them anymore.
我用不着了
I was just angry or annoyed or something.
我只是…
自己在生闷气，我不知道
克蕾婷？
Clem.
好了
Got it.
玛丽今晚会过来
Mary's coming over tonight.
是吗？
Just thought you'd want to know.
对，先知会你一声
我喜欢玛丽
I like when Mary comes to visit.
我喜欢她来访，可惜她不喜欢我
I just don't think she likes me.
她不讨厌你啦
She likes you okay.
我应该找我女朋友过来
So maybe I should invite my girlfriend over.
我交了女朋友
I have a girlfriend now.
随便你
Do whatever you want.
天哪，我…
好吧
我有没有说过我交了新女友？
Did I tell you I have a new girlfriend?
专心一点
We have to focus here.
重点是…
The thing is, my situation is a little weird.
我的情况…
有点诡异
My girlfriend situation.
我女朋友的情况
想也知道
I'm sure it is.
你是…
克蕾婷，我送你回家
Clem, let me drive you home.
滚远一点，变态!
Get out of my face, faggot!
你看!
Look at it out here!
快要荡然无存了
It's all falling apart!
我要消除关于你的记忆
I'm erasing you, and I'm happy!
我很高兴，是你先负我的
You did it to me first!
你竟敢这样对我!
I can't believe you did this to me!
可恶!
Goddamnit!
克蕾婷，听见没？
Clem. Did you hear me?
明天早上你就要消失了
By morning you'll be gone!
这段孽缘划下完美的句点
The perfect ending to this piece of shit story!
有女孩喜欢我… 不行吗？有问题吗？
Is there something wrong with a girl being attracted to me?
没有，只是觉得…
no. I think it's funny.
很好笑
Who do you think's better- looking, me or this guy?
你认为谁比较帅？
我？还是这砘铮
Patrick, let's focus.
专心一点
记不记得上礼拜来的那个女孩？
Remember that girl we did last week?
那个…
The one with the potatoes?
带蛋头先生来的？
那个女孩？
That girl?
对
That's this guy's girlfriend.
她是这砘锏呐朋友
曾经是啦
Was. We took care of that.
我们处理掉了
天哪
我…
我当晚就对她一见钟情
I kind of fell in love with her that night.
什么？
What?
你这个烂人
You little fucker.
怎样？
What?
她毫无意识耶
She was unconscious.
她很漂亮
She was beautiful, and I stole a pair of her panties, too.
我还偷了她的内裤
天哪
Jesus!
怎样？我又不是…
They were clean.
是干净的内裤啦
I don't want to hear this shit.
别告诉我这些事，我不想听
内裤是干净的
They were clean.
什么？别再说了
Stop. We've got work to do.
好
Okay. Fine.
我们还有正事要做
好吧 知道了
报纸拿去
还不只这样
There's more.
她记忆消除了我就约她出去
After we did her, I kind of asked her out.
天哪
Jesus.
你不觉得很不道德吗？
Do you know how unethical...?
没那么严重啦
It's not really that bad.
别作出那种表情，怎样？
Get that look off your face.
What's wrong?
你偷了女生的内裤耶
You stole a girl's panties.
有人闯进来
There's someone here... he stole your underwear.
他偷了你的内裤
我没看到人啊
I don't see anyone.
乔尔，我的靴子呢？
Joel, where are my boots?
你干嘛拿毒药给我？
听不懂英语吗？
我只叫你拿药
给我爱的配方
我快急死了啦
I'm crawling out of my skin!
早知道就把你丢在跳蚤市场
I should have left you at the flea market.
要走了吗？
Want to go?
我想生小孩
I want to have a baby.
改天再说
Let's talk about it later.
不要，我想生小孩
no. I want to have a baby.
我们还没准备好
I don't think we're ready.
你还没准备好
You're not ready.
你自以为能照顾小孩吗？
Do you really think you could take care of a kid?
怎样？
What?
我不想在这里谈
I don't want to talk about it here.
我听不见
I can't hear you.
从来就听不懂你在说什么
I can never understand what you're saying!
我说我不想在这里谈
I said I don't want to talk about this!
什么腹语嘛
We're fucking gonna talk about it!
我们非谈不可
我不想在这里…
You can't just say you don't want to talk about it!
你不能说这种话
别说你不想谈
I'm sorry.
对不起
I'd make a fucking good mother!
我会是个好母亲
我喜欢小孩
I love children.
好啦，你会是个好母亲 我有创意又聪明
I'm creative and I'm smart!
一定会是个好母亲 天哪
问题出在你
It's you, Joel.
你给不起承诺
It's you who can't commit to anything.
快要不见了…
It's going! It's going. You're lucky I'm interested in you.
你不知道我爱上你是你的福气
我头壳坏去才会爱上你
I don't even know why I am.
Maybe I should end it right here! It's over.
或许应该到此为止
Leave you at the flea market, with the costume jewelry!
结束了，结束这段孽缘
把打扮可笑的你丢在跳蚤市场
Maybe you can find a nice antique rocking chair to die in!
说不定你能死在古董摇椅上 我痛苦又困惑
派屈克 玛丽，你好啊
All the pain. Confusion... Hi, Patrick
过来
How's it going, Mary?
外面好冷 这里还好找吧？
It's freezing outside.
还好
Find us okay?
Yeah.
好热情
Hot.
可怜的砘
Poor guy.
有酒喝吗？
Do you have anything real to drink?
没找过
We haven't checked yet.
派屈克？
Patrick?
好的
Let me do the honors.
不，让我去吧
玛丽讨厌我
Mary hates me.
我泡妞技术一级烂
never really had much luck with the ladies.
别再偷女生内裤就好了
Maybe if you stopped stealing their panties.
史丹，还不只如此
不会吧 就是
不会吧
我受够了
你不想喝吧，派屈克？
You didn't want any, did you, Patrick?
我不知道，无所谓
no. That's okay.
等一下
Wait.
祝福健忘的人
Blessed are the forgetful,
因为忘记错误会过得比较好
for they get the better even of their blunders.
尼采说的
That's nietzsche.
摘自“善恶的彼岸”
Beyond Good and Fvil.
我在名人语录里看到的
I found it in my Bartlett's.
名人语录是什么？
What's your Bartlett's?
就是引经据典的书
It's a quote book
收集名人说过的话
It's a book of quotations.
有朝一日霍华也会成为名人
I think Howard will be in Bartlett's one day.
对，霍华有成名的条件
Definitely.
Howard is pure Bartlett's.
天哪
会不会吵醒他？
Can you wake him up?
不可能吵醒他
You can't wake him up.
你什么事都不告诉我
You don't tell me things.
我毫无保留
I'm an open book
什么事都告诉你
I tell you everything.
什么糗事都告诉你
Fvery damn embarrassing thing.
你不信任我
You don't trust me.
碎碎念未必就是沟通
Constantly talking isn't necessarily communicating.
才没有
I don't do that.
我是想了解你
I want to know you.
我没碎碎念
I don't constantly talk
拜托
Jesus.
我们要同甘苦共患难
People have to share things.
这才是亲密关系
That's what intimacy is.
你说这句话我很生气
I'm really pissed that you said that to me!
抱歉
Sorry.
只是我的生活没那么多彩多姿
My life just really isn't that interesting.
我想看你每天日记写些什么
I want to read those journals you're constantly scribbling in.
你会写日记就一定有想法或热情
What do you write if you don't have any thoughts or passions or love?
或是爱
11月19日
november 19th, Two thousand three.
2003年
又在康家小馆吃晚饭
Dinner at Kang's again.
我们和餐厅里那些
Are we like those poor couples
你觉得可悲的情侣一样吗？
you feel...sorry for in restaurants?
只吃饭、不聊天？
Are we the dining dead?
我受不了有人这样看我们
I can't stand the idea of us being a couple people think that about.
我喜欢你的头发
I like that.
鸡肉好不好吃？
How's the chicken?
好吃
Good.
还要吗？
More?
不要了，谢谢
no, thank you.
她一定会喝醉，然后大出洋相
She's going to be drunk and stupid now.
你能不能帮个忙？
Would you do me a favor and clean the goddamn hair...
洗完澡把肥皂上的头发清干净？
off the soap when you're done in the shower?
真的很…
Yeah, it's gross.
对，很恶心
很恶心，我觉得…
令人作呕
I think it's just...
Repulsive.
It's repulsive.
派屈克，快弄完啦
Can we get through this?
派屈克？
Patrick?
橘子妹
Hey, Tangerine.
派屈克，是你啊
Patrick, it's you.
我现在好惨
I'm so miserable right now.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
我不知道
I don't know.
每件事我都搞不清楚
I'm just confused about everything.
What are you confused about?
搞不清楚？
搞不清楚什么？根本没事啊
Fverything's fine.
你爱我吗？
Do you love me?
我当然爱你
Of course I do.
励志的书在哪里？
Where's the self-help section?
你觉得我丑吗？
Do you think I'm ugly?
不会，你很漂亮
no. You're beautiful.
我过去找你
Maybe I should come over.
不用了，我不知道
Oh no. I'm a mess.
我现在好狼狈
我去找你，让你开心一下
Just let me come over. I'll cheer you up.
好吧
Okay.
史丹，我出去一下
Can I leave for a while?
我女友心情不好
My girlfriend's really upset.
我们在消除这个可怜虫的…
We're right in the middle of erasing this poor man's -
让他去吧，史丹
让他去，我来帮忙
Let him go. I'll help.
看吧？
How hard can it be?
有什么困难嘛
She hates me.
她讨厌我，想赶我走
She wants me to go.
去吧
Go.
好
Alright.
我马上过去，橘子妹
I'll be right over, Tangerine.
你喜欢吗？
You like?
天哪
I matched my sweatshirt exactly.
和我的衣服很速配
我喜欢
I like it.
真的？
You look like a tangerine.
你看起来就像一颗橘子
橘子妹克蕾婷
Clemen-teen the tangerine.
美味多汁
Juicy and seedless.
又无籽
I like that.
我喜欢
I like tangerines.
我喜欢橘子
看得出来这是鸭子吗？
Can you see me doing ducks?
看不出来
Tangerine...
鸭子，呱呱
How does he know to call you that?
他怎么知道你叫橘子妹？
谁怎么知道？
How did who know?
天哪
Oh my God. Clem?
酷毙了
克蕾婷？
That's what they called themselves.
那是他们自称的
The Clash, the only band that mattered.
比如知名的冲击合唱团
他们自称冲击是有原因的
And they called themselves that for a reason.
很棒吧？
It's amazing, isn't it?
比如社会正义合唱团，了不起
Like Social Justice.
Yeah, it's totally incredible.
霍华对世人贡献不小
What Howard gives to the world.
是啊
Yeah.
让人们重生
To let people begin again.
功德无量
It's beautiful.
看着纯真无邪的婴儿
You look at a baby, and it's so pure and so free and so...
自由自在又纯洁
clean and...
成年人满脑子悲哀
Adults are this mess of sadness and...
还有恐惧
phobias.
霍华能消除这些记忆
And Howard just makes it all go away.
天哪
宝贝，怎么了？
Baby, what's going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
不知道，我迷失了
I'm lost, I'm scared, I feel like I'm disappearing.
我好害怕
我好像快要消失了
消失？
My skin's coming off!.
我在脱皮，我老了
I'm getting old!
什么事都说不通
nothing makes any sense to me!
你没变老
You're not getting old.
什么事都说不通
nothing makes any sense.
橘子妹…
Tangerine...
什么事都说不通
没事了
It's okay.
Let's go out dancing.
我们出去跳舞
要不要陪我去蒙托克？
You want to go out to Montauk with me?
蒙托克？ 对
Montauk?
不!陪我去波士顿
Yeah. no! Come up to Boston with me.
好，下周末去
Sure. We can go next weekend.
不行，现在就去
no. I have to go now.
我现在就要去
I have to see the frozen Charles now.
我要去看结冰的查理士河
我是乔尔
Hi, it's Joel.
请在哔声之后留话
Leave me a message after the beep and I'll get back to you.
我会尽快回电
接啊
Pick up.
快接啊
等一下…
喂？
Hello? What's up?
什么事？
I got into a little situation with the old lady.
我女朋友有点急事
你今晚一个人可以吗？歹势啦
Can you handle things tonight alone?
I'm really sorry.
没问题，情况控制下来了
Don't worry. I've got it under control.
现在只能顺水推舟
He's on auto-pilot now anyway.
谢了，算我欠你的
Thanks. I owe you big-time.
我要挂电话了
I've got to go.
查理士河
查理士河在哪里？
你看，我们在查理士河上
Look! You and me on the Charles River.
我死而无憾了
I could die right now.
我好快乐
I'm just happy.
从来没有过这种感觉
I've never felt that before.
这里正是我想来的地方
I'm exactly where I want --
我好兴奋
I'm so excited!
我也是
I'm excited, too.
酷毙了
Cool.
这是我送你的…
I got you this thing.
…礼物
祝你情人节快乐
Happy early Valentine's Day.
这是什么？
Wow. What is it?
不知道，拆开来看看
I don't know. Open it up.
好漂亮
It's gorgeous.
喜欢吗？
You like it?
喜欢，正合我意
It's just my taste, really.
天哪
I've never gone out with a guy who bought me jewelry I liked.
前男友都没送过我喜欢的首饰
谢谢你
Thank you.
走吧 好
Joely?
乔尔？
Yeah, Tangerine?
什么事？
我很丑吗？
Am I ugly?
我小时候觉得自己很丑
When I was a kid I thought I was.
我居然说到这儿哭了
Can't believe I'm crying already.
有些人…
Sometimes I think people don't understand
不知道当小孩有多孤单
how lonely it is to be a kid.
一点也不在乎
我八岁时有好多玩具和洋娃娃
Like you don't matter.
So, I'm eight...
我最喜欢一个丑娃娃
and I have these toys, these dolls.
My favorite is this ugly girl doll who I call Clementine.
我叫她“克蕾婷” 我一直对她大叫…
And I keep yelling at her You can't be ugly!
“你不能当丑小鸭”
“要变天鹅”
Be pretty!
好奇怪
It's weird.
若我有魔法能让她变身
Like if I can transform her...
我也会让自己变身
I would magically change, too.
你很漂亮
You're pretty.
乔尔…
Joely. Don't ever leave me.
不要离开我
你很漂亮…
You're pretty.
莫兹维…
Please let me keep this memory.
请你让我保留这段记忆
这一段就好
Just this one.
我想握住你的手，来嘛
I want to hold your hand. Come on.
别闹了
Stop it!
我现在死而无憾了
I could die right now.
我实在是…
I'm just... so happy.
太快乐了
我从来没有过这种感觉
I've never felt that before.
这里正是…
I'm just exactly...
我想来的地方
where I want to be.
克蕾婷？
Clem.
我想就此打住
I want to call it off.
我会提示你
我想就此打住
I want to call it off.
听见没？我不想玩了! 停下来!
Can you hear me?!
I want to call it off!.
有人在吗？
Is anybody there?!!
克蕾婷？
乔尔？
Joel.
克蕾…
乔尔？
I am.
克蕾婷!
Joel.
乔尔？
克蕾婷!
怎么了？
快走 快走
We've got to go. What? Where?
怎么了？去哪儿？
我知道该怎么停止了
I have an idea of how to stop this.
停止什么？
Stop what?
乔尔…
Joel. Come on.
快点
不…别搔我痒，不要啦
Don't tickle me.
你闻闻看
no! Don't!
闻我的胳肢窝
Smell my armpits!
别闹了
专心一点
Concentrate, Clem. We've got to get back to the office.
克蕾婷
我们要回到办公室
万圣节
Halloween.
有一台录音机
There was a tape recorder.
不行，别碰那张照片
no, not the picture!
找到了
Back here.
就在这里，快点
Come on!
看着我
Look at me. I want to go there!
我想去那里
我们的资料都要保密
Our files are confidential, Mister Barish,
所以不能拿证据给你看
so I can't show you evidence.
我只能说…
Suffice it so say that Miss Chryzinski...
库钦斯基小姐过得不快乐
was not happy and she wanted to move on.
她想抛弃过往
冷静下来，告诉我…
Just tell me everything you remember.
告诉我你记得的每件事
That's what he said.
他只说了这句话
然后…
What did we see that day?
我们当天看到了什么？
不，等一下…
Oh, look!
你看!
可恶!
We're going to see my grandma!
我们要去看我祖母
不行，别搭火车
no. We're not going on a train.
为什么？我不想…
Joel, please.
求求你，别叫我用跑的
Don't make me run!
快点!
Come on. Mierzwiak!
莫兹维!
非跑不可吗？
Do we always have to run?
莫兹维!
求求你
Please?
先告诉我你记得的每件事…
Why don't we begin by you telling me everything
莫兹维!叫醒我!
you can remember -
Mierzwiak! Wake me up!
抱歉，我以为你知道后果会如何
I'm sorry.
I thought you understood what was going on here.
我不知道
You're erasing her from me.
你要把她从我记忆中消除
你要把我从她记忆中消除
You're erasing me from her.
我不知道
你用一种机器
You have this thing.
我躺在床上，我有意识
I'm in my bed. I know it.
我进入了我的大脑里
I'm in my brain.
我也是你想像出来的
I'm part of your imagination, too.
你要我怎么帮你？
How can I help you from there?
我也在你的大脑里，我就是你
I'm inside your head, too.
I'm you!
对不起
Sorry.
他是谁？
Who's that?
他是我们的员工，名叫…
He works for us. That's...
派屈克宝贝
Paaaaaa-trick..baaaaaby boy.
他假冒我的身份
He's stealing my identity.
他偷了我的东西
He stole my stuff.
他用我的话和礼物勾引我女友
He's seducing my girlfriend with my words.
他偷了她的内裤
He stole her underwear.
天哪，他偷了她的内裤
Jesus Christ. He stole her underwear.
我现在死而无憾了
I could die right now. I'm just happy.
我好快乐
从来没有过那种感觉
I've never felt that before.
这里正是我想来的地方
I'm exactly where I want to be.
我想回家
I want to go home.
什么？
What?
克蕾婷!
Clem!
等等我!
Wait, Clem!
他们要把你从我记忆中消除
Clem, they're erasing you.
不，你看这边
Over here!
专心一点
Focus. I hired them.
他们是我花钱请来的
I'm sorry. I'm so stupid.
抱歉，是我愚蠢
冷静下来，好好欣赏风景
Sweetie, calm down.
我要阻止他们
Fnjoy the scenery.
免得醒来就忘记你了
I need it to stop before I wake up and don't know you any more.
好啊
直接叫他们取消嘛
Just tell them to cancel it then.
你在胡说什么？
What are you talking about?
不能取消，我陷入昏迷了
I can't just cancel it. I'm asleep.
你自己醒过来啊
Wake yourself up.
好吧，要我醒过来吗？
Want me to wake up?
好，没问题
Okay.
来吧，要我尝试你才满意吗？
This make you happy if I try?
对
Yeah. I'll try really hard.
我会努力的
Here we go. That was a great idea.
来吧，好主意
就这样
好了
效果不错嘛
That's working like gangbusters.
天哪，我好痒
天哪，这是什么？天哪，这… 这是胎记啦
That tickles me!
What the hell is that?
你是怎么弄的？
It's a birthmark!
刚才有用
It did work, for a second.
可是我没办法…
看吧？
See?
我动弹不得
But I couldn't move.
这不也是乔尔打算
Isn't that just another one of Joel's self-fulfilling prophecies?
自己实现的预言吗？
It's more important to prove me wrong than to actually -
最好证明我错了，不要…
I don't want to discuss this right now, okay?
我现在不想讨论这个
好吧
Fine.
不然要怎样？
Then what? I'm listening.
我洗耳恭听
I don't know.
我不知道
You erased me.
你消除了对我的记忆
That's why I'm doing this.
所以我才会来这里
这就是我当初的来意
I'm sorry.
对不起
你…
You know me. I'm impulsive.
你最了解我，我向来很冲动
我就是喜欢这样的你
That's what I love about you.
乔尔？
Joel.
我有另一个解决办法
I have another idea for this problem.
有个关于我的回忆
This is a memory of me.
你看过我的阴部之后
The way you wanted to...
have sex on the couch after you look down at my crotch.
就想和我在沙发上做爱
那两个芭辣助手快要来了
Joel. The eraser guys are coming here,
你带我走 去不属于我的地方
so what if you took me someplace else....
somewhere where I don't belong, and we hide there till morning?
我们在那里躲到天亮
我的每段记忆里都有你
I can't remember anything without you.
我好感动，但请你想想看
That's very sweet, but try.
好吧
Okay.
Row, row, row your boat gently down the stream...
merrily, merrily, merrily, merrily, life is but a dream.
“船儿划呀划”
“缓缓顺流而下”
“好快乐呀，可惜人生如梦”
成功了
It's working!
我是天才
I'm a genius!
乔尔？
Joel.
你在哪里？
Where did you go?
我也要一起去
I'm supposed to come, too!
我要去拿沙拉碗
I'll get a salad bowl.
帮我搅拌汤，顺便看着乔尔
Can you stir the soup and keep an eye on ?
好啊
He just likes to be near me.
他喜欢黏着我
Absolutely.
好，没问题
克蕾婷？
It worked. My God!
成功了
天哪!你看!
Look at this! It worked!
成功了
Look at this dress!
你看看这件衣服
天哪，真希望我可以带走
I wish I could take it with me.
我是谁？
Hey, who am I?
汉林太太
Mrs. Hamlyn.
对，汉林太太
Right. Mrs. Hamlyn.
我才四岁
I must be about four.
天哪
Oh, my gosh.
找到沙拉碗了
Found the salad bowl,
我要准备沙拉和四季豆
so I'm serving salad and string beans.
他还好吧？
Is he okay under there?
甜心，你好不好？
Honey, are you alright?
天哪
Would you hate me if I asked you to clean some string beans?
我真想打扫一整天
你能不能帮我洗四季豆？
没问题
not at all.
天哪，我好喜欢这间厨房
I love this kitchen.
谢谢你
Thank you so much.
她没在看我
She's not looking at me.
这…
She's busy.
她在忙，根本没在看我
no one ever looks at me.
从来没人看着我
我要妈妈
I want my mommy.
乔尔宝贝
Oh, baby Joel.
乔尔…
Is every little peanut under there okay?
小宝贝还好吧？
他很好
He's fine.
你有没有喝的？
Do you have something to drink?
这么早喝鸡尾酒可以吗？
Could you drink a cocktail at this hour?
我知道还不到五点
I know it's not five, but --
可是我好想喝伏特加
I would die for a vodka.
我去找找看
Let me check if I have that.
好，我在这里等你
Okay.
乔尔，不行
I'm just going to wait right here.
乔尔？
no, sweetie.
不行，你妈要我看着你
Joel?
Your mother wants me to mind you.
回去桌子底下
Get back under the table.
冰淇淋…
Ice cream.
不行，吃完晚饭才能吃
not until after you've had your dinner.
别闹了，乔尔
Come on! Grow up.
别孩子气了
Don't leave me, Clem.
别离开我，天哪
Oh, my God.
没有，我在这里
This is sort of warped.
有点变态
我害怕
I'm scared.
我要妈妈
I want my mommy!
别哭了，乔尔宝贝
Don't cry, baby Joel.
乔尔宝贝，没事
It's okay.
乔尔？
Joel! Stop it! I think it's working.
乔尔!别闹了!
好像有用了，你看
We're hidden, Joel. Look!
我们躲起来了
你看
等一下
Wait there.
你看我的下体
My crotch is still here, just as you remembered it.
和你记忆中一样
好恶
停下来了
It stopped.
什么？
What?
停止消除记忆了
It stopped erasing.
糟糕
Oh, shit! This is terrible.
大事不妙了
他偏离蓝图了
He's off the map.
Where?
哪里？
I don't know where!
我不知道
我不知道哪里
糟糕，大事不妙了
This is very bad news.
我的眼镜呢？
Where are my glasses?
好吧
Crap! What did we do?
死定了
现在怎么办？
What shall we do?
我们该怎么办？
I don't know what to do.
我不知道怎么办
我们该怎么办？
What shall we do?
完蛋了，我不知道
I just said I don't know.
我刚才说了不知道怎么办
I'm sorry.
对不起，我们怎么办？
What shall we do?
我不知道
I don't know. Mellow out.
放轻松，你弄得我很紧张
You're freaking me out.
我们…
快想办法
We have to do something.
好吧 他醒来后可能会大脑受损
He could wake up all half-baked.
安静点，你弄得我很紧张
Quiet. You're freaking me out.
狼狈不堪
All gooey and half-baked.
大脑又烤熟了
That sounds so good. I'm hungry.
好吧
好像不错
可恶!
我饿了
Oh, shit. What? What?
可恶
怎样…
打电话给霍华
We should call Howard!
不行，我自己就能搞定
no! I can handle this.
你不能打电话给霍华
他大脑受损了
You can't call Howard.
没时间让你胡闹
There's no time to fuck around.
我应付得来，你少胡说了
I've got this under control.
别胡闹了
What are you talking about? Stop fucking around!
好，我打电话给霍华
Okay. I'll call Howard.
喂？
Hello?
霍华吗？
Howard? It's Stan.
我是史丹
I'm working on this guy down here...
我来替这砘锵除记忆
刚才有点不太对颈
and we seem to have lost him for a moment.
我叫不醒他了
And I can't bring him back up.
好吧
Tell me what happened before he disappeared.
告诉我事情出错之前出了什么事
我不太确定，因为我暂时离开
I wasn't sure because I was away from the monitor for a minute...
我让机器自动执行，因为我要…
and I had it on auto-pilot because I had to pee.
我要去尿尿
Where was Patrick?
派屈克呢？
Patrick? He had to go home sick
派屈克？
派屈克不舒服回家去了
天哪，地址给我
我知道，真对不起
What's the address?
没关系，快说吧
I'm so sorry.
这里是南村路159号
I'm at 1 59 South Village.
好
Apartment 1-F.
洛克维尔中心1E公寓
玛丽？
Rockville Center.
什么事？
Mary? He's coming right now.
他马上过来
我留下来
I'm staying.
快去收拾东西
Get your stuff. I see.
我要留下来
你先走吧
I think you should go.
才不要
no.
玛丽…
我吸了大麻
I am so stoned.
拜托你快走吧
Please, you have to go.
别再吸大麻了
我不想让他看到吸了大麻的我
I don't want him to see me stoned.
我们惹了天大的麻烦，若霍华…
You have no idea how much trouble we'd get into if Howard comes -
可恶，我好狼狈
乔尔，住手!你看!乔尔!
Joel, stop! Look!
乔尔!
I want her to pick me up.
叫她来接我
It's weird how strong that desire is.
那种欲望强烈得很诡异
乔尔!看着我，快看
Look at me!
你明天早上会记得我
You'll remember me in the morning...
你会来找我 谈我们的事，我们重新开始
and you'll come to me,
派特？
and you'll tell me about us, and we'll start over.
我刚才…派特？
Pat? I thought we could have a little cocktail.
不是要喝鸡尾酒吗？
那个派屈克在假冒我
That Patrick guy, he's copying me.
哪个派屈克？
What Patrick guy?
那砘!
That guy! He's here.
什么？
他来过了
In my apartment.
在我的住处
One of the eraser guys.
他是芭辣助手之一
在替你消除记忆时爱上了你
He fell for you when they were doing you,
现在他假装不认识你
and now he's...introduced himself like he doesn't know you
你们在交往
and you guys are dating.
真的吗？
Really? Is he cute?
他帅不帅？
你没什么不对颈
There's nothing wrong with you.
你是我见过最好的女孩
You're the most wonderful person I've ever met.
你很善良
You're kind and beautiful and smart...
人长得漂亮
又聪明风趣
and funny and nice.
人很好
什么？
What?!
好吧
Okay.
走啊…快点
Move! Come on, let's go!
小心点
我们走!
天哪，我还没清醒
I'm still stoned.
你给我的眼药水没啥屁用
Those eyedrops you gave me didn't do shit.
别激动
Be cool.
玛丽，你怎么来了？
Hello, Mary. What are you doing here?
霍华，她只是来帮忙
Hi, Howard. She was just here to help out.
我想深入了解整个流程
I wanted to understand as much about the procedure as possible.
我有必要搞清楚 整个工作内容
I think it's important for my job to understand the inner workings of...
不是我的工作，而是同事的工作
the work that we do.
Well, not that I do, but the work that is done...
by people where I also work
The work of my colleagues.
好，先看看有没有办法可以解决
Let's see if we can get to the bottom of this, shall we?
好的
奇怪了
That's odd.
已经试过了
Already tried that.
有没有试过C路径？
You tried going through the C-gate?
当然有
Of course.
我是说…有啊
I mean yes.
好吧
好了
Alright.
你要连线吗？
You want to get linked up?
对
好的
我启动了应用程式
I already ran the utility programs, and I have nothing there...
结果没用
于是我检查与资料不符的记忆
so I checked all the memories against the printed logs.
好吧
Here, Howard.
霍华，这把椅子给你坐
I got you a chair. Thank you.
谢谢你
You're welcome.
坐吧
Alright.
不客气
好，我来处理
I've got it.
我要浏览整个记忆
I'm going through the entire memory, see if something comes up.
看看有没有蛛丝马迹
我喜欢泡在水槽里洗澡
I love being bathed in the sink
很有安全感
Such a feeling of security.
我没看过你这么开心
I've never seen you happier, Baby Joel.
找到了
There it is.
我不懂怎么会偏离蓝图这么多
I don't understand why it's off the map like that.
他在搞什么鬼？
What was he doing there?
他睁开眼睛了
His eyes are open.
之前有这样吗？
Has this happened before with him?
没有
no.
情况不太妙
This is not good.
我要…
先给他打一针
I'm going to have to give him this.
安东，你看不出来我爱你吗？
Can't you see I love you, Antoine?
好，恢复正常了
Okay. We're back in.
看着霍华真是赏心悦目
That was beautiful to watch Howard, like a surgeon or a concert pianist.
好像外科医生或在演奏的钢琴家
谢谢你，玛丽
Thank you, Mary.
霍华，去睡一下，我应该搞得定
Howard, you should get some sleep.
I think I'll be fine now.
安东，你看不出来我爱你吗？
Can't you see I love you, Antoine?
我好幸运，亲一个
Lucky me. Lay one on me.
别叫我安东
Don't call me Antoine.
我叫沃利
My name is Wally.
我知道
Yes, I know,
但怎么会有女人
but how can a woman love a man with a name like Wally?
爱上叫沃利的男人？
Oh! What was that?
什么声音？
天哪，有人从你屁股跑出来
My God, there's people coming out of your butt.
真的吗？
There is?
好了
Got it.
橘子妹!
Tangerine! Come on.
乔尔，你在干嘛？
我们快走
We've got to go.
快点，跟我走，求求你快走
Go on. Please go.
你跑得了一时，躲不了一世
You can run, but you can't hide.
克蕾婷，快点!
Clem, come on! There I am.
在那里
卡车
Doc?
医生？
求求你
Please?
好吧，先告诉我…
Let's begin by telling me everything you remember -
你记得的每一件事…
好奇怪，他在回忆我们消除的事
That's strange.
He's in a memory we've already eased.
至少我们知道他在想什么
At least we know where he is.
他回归轨道了
He's back on track, right?
走吧
Come on, Clem.
他好像在抗拒整个流程
Seems he's developed some sort of resistance to the procedure.
不要，我不想再跑了
I don't want to run any more.
可恶!
Shit!
快点…
Come on...
把我藏在地底下埋起来
Hide me somewhere deeper, somewhere really buried.
哪里？
Where?
藏在你的羞耻里
Hide me in your humiliation.
羞耻
Come on, you big baby.
来啊，乳臭未干的小子
对不起
我送你回家
不!
no!!
再见了，霍华
Bye, Howard.
霍华，等一下!
他又出状况了
Wait! He's disappeared again.
天哪
Oh, dear.
我很遗憾，霍华
I'm so sorry.
羞耻
Humiliation.
乔尔
Joel.
羞耻
我也不喜欢
I don't like it either.
只是想找出可怕的藏匿所…
I'm just trying to find horrible secret places to -
乔尔，我要给你一个惊喜
Honey, I have a surprise.
我…
You know what? I'll just ask you in the morning.
这样吧，我明天早上再问你
晚安
Goodnight.
不，对不起，乔尔
I'm sorry Joel. Shut up.
乔尔
闭嘴 乔尔!
乔尔，你看
Joel, look where we are!
看什么？
你看这是哪里
克蕾婷，这样不好
This isn't good.
把我藏起来
Hide me somewhere really buried.
埋在地底下
快打啊…
Hit it, Joel!
不行，我要回家了
I can't. I've got to go home.
待会儿再说
I'll do it later!
他有女朋友
He has a girlfriend.
等一下，我在干嘛？ 男生爱女生
What am I doing?
弗瑞迪，你再也吓唬不了我
Freddy, you don't scare me anymore!
乔尔
Joel, get up.
乔尔，快起来
Come on. They're not worth it.
快点，不值得这样
他们不值得你这样
He's not listening! Come on.
他没在听
快点啊
Stupid!
笨蛋!
我好丢脸
I'm so ashamed.
没关系，你还小嘛
It's okay.
You were a little kid.
对啊
Come on.
走吧
That's where I live - lived.
我住这里…以前啦
真希望我小时候就认识你
I wish I knew you when I was a kid.
你喜欢我的粉红帽吗？
Do you like my pink hat?
给你，舒服多了
Look, feel better.
这次你可以杀了我，轮到我了
You can really kill me this time. Go.
来吧，一、二、三
You're really going to die, though, right?
可以吗？你真的会死吧？
好吧
One two three...
一、二、三
你死了
You're dead.
我妈妈
Oh, my mom.
没事，我们在闹着玩
It's okay!
嗨，乔尔的妈妈 不是真的
We're playing.
他要杀了我
It's not real. He's killing me.
你死了吗？
Are you dead yet?
你死了
You're dead!
应该没问题了，我还是不明白
I think I got the hang of this.
I still don't understand it...
但快要找到他了
but I'm finding him quickly enough.
克蕾婷!
克蕾…
乔尔？
Joel.
你没事吧？
Are you okay?
乔尔？
Joel...
天哪，你好过份
Oh my God, that was terrible.
好了啦
Almost three seconds. Alright.
将近三秒钟
好，再让我试一次
Let me be it one more time..
再试一次我就要走了
One more, then I get to go.
好
可恶!
酷毙了!
Oh, shit!
好酷，小心点!
This is so cool!
Look out!
It's fluff!.
好软哦!
我们的房子!
Our house!
走吧
等一下，我们该走了
We've got to go!
来嘛
Come on!
我们该走了，克蕾婷
Clem, we've got to go.
我们该走了
真是的!快点! 好耶
This is a really bad time for this!
现在不是闹着玩的时候
好恶心，天哪
我连要去哪里都不知道
I don't even know where we're going.
一定很好玩，走吧
It's going to be fun.
那里很好玩，不对，走这边
It's the best place - this way. no, this way.
不对，是这边
This way. Come on.
不…走这边，快点
不对…
You're no help at all.
你在帮倒忙
快走…
Come on.
放开我!
Let go of me, Joel!
我喜欢看你工作，霍华
I like watching you work, Howard.
我想…
I guess I'll go out for some air.
我想出去…
透透气
If nobody minds.
希望你们不介意
情况好像控制下来了
It looks like you have everything under control here.
对，确实…
没事了
That's fine.
你喜欢引经据典吗？
Do you like quotes?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
就是…
Famous quotes.
引用名人的话
我觉得很有启发性
I find reading them inspirational...
我在看书时…
and I've come across some I thought you might like, too.
找到了一些你可能会喜欢的句子
说来听听
I'd love to hear some.
有一句话是说…
Blessed are the forgetful,
祝福健忘的人
for they get the better even of their blunders.
因为忘记错误会过得比较好
尼采说的？
That's nietzsche, right?
对
Yeah. And I thought I could tell you something you didn't know.
我可以说些你不知道的
没关系，这句话很好
It's a good quote.
很高兴我们都听过
I'm happy we both know it.
是啊
还有一段我也很喜欢
There's this other one I like.
亚历山大波普说的…
It's by Pope Alexander, and it goes -
亚历山大波普？
Alexander Pope?
对了，真是的
Oh, yeah.
我想着别说出这个名字自讨没趣
Shit.
It's just that I told myself not to say Pope Alexander ...
结果还是说出口了
and sound like a dope, and then I go ahead and say it.
没关系啦
It's no big deal.
你真好
You're such a sweetheart.
那句话是说…
The quote goes
“纯洁无辜的人太幸福了”
How happy is the blameless vestal's lot!
“世人都健忘，遗忘了世人”
The world forgetting, by the world forgot:
“纯净的心里有永恒的阳光”
Fternal sunshine of the spotless mind!
“祷告都应验”
Fach prayer accepted and each wish resign'd.
“愿望都得以偿”
I want to be a huge elephant.
我想当一头超级大的…
大象
长着这么大的鼻子
With a huge trunk, like that.
克蕾婷？
Clementine?
I haven't heard that one.
那段话我没听过
说得真好
It's lovely.
我认为说得非常贴切
I just thought it would be appropriate, maybe.
我很崇拜你的工作
I really admire the work you do
我不是故意要这么冒昧…
I don't mean to be so familiar -
没关系
It's fine. I'm happy to hear -
我喜欢听
对不起
I'm sorry.
我暗恋你很久了
I've loved you for a very long time.
我不应该说这种话的
I shouldn't have said that.
没关系，你是个好女孩
Mary, you're a wonderful girl.
可是我…
But you know I have a wife and kids.
我有妻小了，你也知道的
玛丽
Mary.
我们不能这样
Oh. Mary we can't do this.
早安，莫兹维太太
Good morning, Mrs. Mierzwiak
怎么了？
Oh my God. Who is it?
天哪
是谁？
史丹，多谢你的鸡婆
Thanks a lot, Stan.
荷莉丝!
Hollis!
等一下…荷莉丝？
Wait.
我就知道，霍华
I knew it, Howard.
刚开始不是这样，我是来工作的
It didn't start out like this.
莫兹维太太…
I came here to work!
我是一时胡涂了 是真的，我是暗恋他的傻女孩
This is a one-time mistake.
it's true! I'm a stupid girl with a crush!
他是被我逼得半推半就
I basically forced him into it!
你太过份了，快告诉她
Don't be a monster.
Tell the girl.
告诉我什么？
Tell me what?
可怜的孩子
Oh, you poor kid.
他是你的人了
You can have him.
你们有过一段情
You did.
什么？
What?!
我们有过一段情
We have a history.
抱歉，是你想消除记忆的
I'm sorry.
You wanted the procedure done.
你想这么做
You wanted it done so you could get past...
忘掉…
我要去办正事，天快亮了
I have to finish the work in there.
It's almost morning.
我们待会儿再谈
We'll talk later.
好吗？
Okay?
我送你回家
Let me give you a lift home.
天哪，讨厌死了
你好
Hi.
我以为你不想再见到我了
Didn't figure you'd show your face around me again.
你可能觉得…
I thought you were humiliated.
很丢脸
You did run away, after all.
你当场就跑掉了
我只是想见你一面 然后…
I just needed to see you, and...
怎样？
我想…
I'd like to take you out or something.
约你出去
你结婚了
You're married.
还没，没有结婚
not yet.
no, I'm not married.
我没有结婚
我直截了当告诉你，我很黏人
Look, I'm telling you right off the bat
I'm high maintenance, so...
我不会…
I'm not gonna tiptoe around your marriage or...
介入你的婚姻，不管你在想什么
想和我在一起就别乱来
whatever it is you've got going there.
If you want to be with me, you're with me.
好吧
Okay.
太多男人把我概念化
Too many guys think I'm a concept, or I complete them, or...
要我让他们的人生圆满
说我给他们活着的感觉
I'm gonna make them alive.
我是个坏女孩，想求得心灵平静
I'm just a fucked-up girl who's... looking for my own peace of mind.
别把我当成你的
Don't assign me yours.
我还记得那一段话
I remember that speech really well.
我看穿你了，对吧？
I had you pegged, didn't I?
你看穿了全人类
You had the whole human race pegged.
或许吧
Probably.
我还是觉得你会救我一命
I still thought you were going to save my life.
即使经过了那件事
Fven after that.
我知道
I know.
若我们可以重新来过
It would be different if we could just give it another go-round.
情况就会不一样了
记住我
Remember me.
尽你的全力
Try your best.
或许我们能重新开始
Maybe we can.
好，告诉我你记得什么
Just tell me what you remember, and we'll take it from there.
接着就交给我们吧
好
Okay.
我对你一见钟情
I liked you immediately.
你对我没非份之想
You didn't come on to me at all.
我喜欢
I liked that.
刚开始我跟你说话结结巴巴的
I was so tongue-tied around you at first.
但我想让你觉得我很聪明
But I wanted you to think I was smart.
我等不及想来上班
I couldn't wait to come to work
我幻想…
I had these fantasies of...
我们结婚生子
us being married and having kids and just...
霍华，我办不到
Oh, Howie, I can't do this.
我们说好了这样做最好
We agreed it's for the best, Mary.
我知道
I know.
天哪
Oh, God!
我抬下面，你…
I'll take the bottom and you
不行…来吧 我搬得动
Joel...help me with that.
乔尔，帮个忙
你要我搬吗？
Will you get the cooler?
好，谢谢
你去搬冰箱 冰箱很…
She can get it.
这很轻吧？ 她搬得动…
Let me get that.
我来搬，让我来搬，不…
no, no, no!
你别动
Don't take anything. I can take the plane.
我可以拿飞机
Put the gate back up.
放下来，把门关好
这是我们刚认识那天
This is the day we met.
你在海边
You were down by the surf.
我从远处就看见了你
I could just make you out in the distance.
还记得当时就被你吸引了
I remember being drawn to you, even then.
我觉得好奇怪
I thought Wow. How odd.
我爱上了你的背影
I'm drawn to someone's back
你穿着橘色衣服，那件你常穿
You were in that orange sweatshirt...
I would come to know so well.
最后我甚至讨厌它
And even hate, eventually.
但当时我心想…
But at the time I thought How cool, an orange sweatshirt.
酷毙了，橘色的衣服耶
你好
Hi, there.
Hi.
我看到你坐在那里
I saw you sitting over here.
自己一个人
By yourself.
我心想…
And I thought Thank God...
谢天谢地
someone normal who doesn't know
总算有个正常人也不懂社交应对
how to interact at these things either.
我向来不太会说话
I don't ever know what to say.
我叫克蕾婷
I'm Clementine.
能不能吃一块你的鸡肉？
Can I borrow a piece of your chicken?
你就直接吃了
And then you just took it, without waiting for an answer.
没等我同意
好亲密
It was so intimate, like we were already lovers.
仿佛我们已经是情侣了
我叫乔尔
I'm Joel.
嗨，乔尔
Hi, Joel.
别取笑我的名字
no jokes about my name.
你是说…
Like Oh, my darlin', oh, my darlin', oh, my darlin' Clementine?
“亲爱的…亲爱的小柑橘”吗？
那首卡通主题曲？
Huckleberry Hound? That sort of thing?
对 不会啦
Yeah. Like that.
就是那样
no, no jokes.
我不会取笑你的
我小时候最喜欢的
One of my favorite things
就是那个卡通的玩偶
when I was a kid was my Huckleberry Hound doll.
我觉得你的名字很奇妙
I think your name is magical.
到此为止
This is it, Joel.
快要被消除了
It's gonna be gone soon.
我知道
I know.
现在怎么办？
What do we do?
好好享受
Fnjoy it.
你结婚了吗？
You married?
没有
no.
我们搬过来住吧
Let's move into this neighborhood.
但有人和我一起住
I do sort of live with someone, though.
男的女的？
Male or female?
什么？
What? Female.
女的
至少你不是同性恋
At least I'm not barking up the wrong tree.
你认识这些人吗？
Do you know these people?
当然不认识，过来
Of course not. Come on.
他们可能有养狗
They might have a dog.
没有狗啦
There's no dog.
你要干嘛？
What are you doing?
外面好冷
It's freezing out.
我真不敢相信
I don't believe this.
克蕾婷!
进来
过来，淹水也没关系
Come on. The water's fine.
今晚没人会来，相信我
nobody's coming here tonight, believe me.
好暗
你…
So what's your girlfriend's name?
你女朋友叫什么名字？
娜欧蜜，但我们不算是…
naomi, but we're not really...
我们…
无所谓啦
Whatever.
这样好舒服，现在我想找…
So this is great.
now I can look for...
蜡烛、火柴
candles, matches, and the liquor cabinet.
还有酒窖
Oh, God.
天哪
我们该走了
I think we should go.
电话不通
There's no phone line.
你说什么？
What?
我们该走了
I think we should go.
为什么？
Why? It's our house.
这是我们的房子
只过一夜嘛
Just for tonight.
我们是大卫与露丝拉斯金夫妇
We are...David and Ruth Laskin!
你想当哪一个？
Which one...do you want to be?
我比较想当露丝
I prefer to be Ruth, but I can be flexible.
但都可以啦
你要什么？
What do you need?
酒
Alcohol.
天哪
So, are you okay with wine?
你喝不喝葡萄酒？ 我不知道
你来挑选葡萄酒
I don't know...
我去找卧房，打扮成…
Well, you choose the wine.
I'll go find the bedroom and slip into something more Ruth.
露丝
我现在没有露丝的感觉
I'm Ruth-less at the moment.
我们真的该走了
我还得赶车
I've got to catch my ride.
那就去吧
So go.
结果我走了
I did.
我当你是个疯子
I thought maybe you were a nut.
但你充满刺激感
But you were exciting.
可惜你没留下来
I wish you'd stayed!
我也很后悔没留下来
I wish I'd stayed, too.
现在好后悔
now I wish I'd stayed.
我后悔很多事
I wish I'd done a lot of things.
天哪，真希望我…
I wish I'd stayed.
我好后悔没留下来
真的
I do.
我下楼时你已经走了
I came back downstairs, and you were gone.
我走了
I walked out the door.
我踏出了门外
为什么？
Why?
我不知道
I don't know.
我好像变成受惊的小孩
I felt like a scared little kid.
我满脑子浆糊，什么都不知道
It was above my head. I don't know.
你觉得害怕？
You were scared?
对
我以为你早就知道了
Thought you knew that about me.
我跑回营火堆旁
I ran back to the bonfire,
大概是想摆脱羞耻感吧
trying to outrun my humiliation, I think
我是不是说错了什么？
Was it something I said?
对
Yeah.
你说“那就去吧”
You said So go with such disdain.
用轻蔑的口气
对不起
I'm sorry.
没关系啦
It's okay.
乔尔？
Joel.
若你这次留下来呢？
What if you stayed this time?
我踏出了门外
I walked out the door.
记忆荡然无存了
There's no memory left.
至少回来说声再见吧
Come back and make up a goodbye, at least.
我们假装时光倒转
Let's pretend we had one.
再见了，乔尔
Bye, Joel.
我爱你
I love you.
我们蒙托克见
Meet me in Montauk
飞机不是我弄坏的
I didn't crash the plane.
它自己摔坏了，不是我弄的
The plane crashed.
I didn't do it.
你用遥控器操纵飞机
You were operating the plane with the remote control,
and it crashed.
结果摔坏了
It was fucking windy. Come on.
风太大了，别再碎碎念
You're stoned and you're driving.
你吸了大麻还开车
The pot balances it out and brings you back up.
对，吸大麻能维持我们的关系
That's why I smoke it.
让我迷迷糊糊，所以我才吸大麻 若要喝酒，不如吸大麻
If I'm going to be drinking, then
I'll smoke it.
真的啦，有医学研究
It does.
在科学网路上证实了
A medical test was done by the Science network
小心看路
Honey, just watch the road.
我什么也看不见
I can't see shit.
我看到你在和美女搭讪
I saw you talking to somebody pretty.
她人很好
She was nice.
对，她是谁？
Who was it?
她是…
She was just a girl.
就是普通的女孩嘛
你真的…
好了
我先把车子停在路边
So I've got to drop the van off.
谢谢你，史丹
Thanks, Stan.
我们聊一聊
We'll talk
你的东西好多
You've got a lot of your stuff there. That's right.
对，我东西很多
I take it you're not coming back
我想你不会回来了
我是为了你才回来的
I wouldn't come back if I was you.
你发誓毫不知情吗？
Do you swear you didn't know?
我发誓
I swear.
你没有消除记忆？
So you didn't do the erasing?
当然没有，天地良心啊
Of course not.
你甚至没怀疑我们交往过？
And you never even suspected we were together?
可能有一次吧
Once, maybe.
我下班回来，你在他车上
I was coming back from a job, and I saw you two talking.
我看到你们俩在聊天
我向你挥手，你还笑了
So I waved to you, and you giggled.
我看起来怎样？
How did I look?
你看起来很开心
You looked happy.
享受偷情的快感
Happy with a secret.
然后呢？
And after that?
我就没再撞见你们约会了
I never saw you two together again like that...
于是我以为是自己胡思乱想
so I just figured I was imagining things.
我很喜欢你，玛丽
I really like you, Mary Svevo.
你知道吗？
You know that?
谢谢你
Thanks.
我去拿牙刷
Let me get my toothbrush.
好
克蕾婷，你在哪里？
Where are you, Clem?
我好担心，你好像在生我的气
I'm worried.
I feel like you're mad at me and I don't know what I did.
不知道我做错了什么
我做错了什么？我好爱你
I love you so much.
我会不惜代价让你快乐
I'll do anything to make you happy.
你要我怎么做？我一定照办
Just tell me what you want me to do, and I'll do it.
我早上会过去确定你没事
I'm going to stop by this morning, just to make sure you're okay.
我们走吧
Vamonos, senor.
我昨晚玩得很愉快
I had a really nice time last night.
愉快？
nice?
昨晚是我这辈子最快乐的时光
I had the best fucking night of my entire fucking life last night.
这才像话嘛
That's better.
好奇怪
This is weird.
给霍华莫兹维的所有病患…
To all patients of Doctor Howard Mierzwiak..
我叫玛丽
My name is Mary Svevo.
我们见过，但你们不记得我了 我任职于…
We've met, but you don't remember me.
我们见过，但你们不记得我了
I worked for a company you hired to have part of your memory erased.
我任职于你们委托消除记忆的… 我任职于你们委托
消除记忆的公司 后来我觉得这样做太可怕…
I've since decided that this is a horrible...
好像是什么广告吧
为了弥补罪过
To correct this,
我要把档案还给你们
I'm sending everyone's file back to them.
我叫克蕾婷
My name is Clementine Kruscynski.
我要消除对乔尔的记忆
I'm here to erase Joel Barish.
这是什么？
What is this?
我不知道
I don't know.
他很无趣
He's boring.
这够理由消除对他的记忆吧？
Is that enough reason to erase someone?
我最近经常在想以前和现在的我
I've been thinking how I was before and how I am now, and he changed me.
他好像改变了我
I feel like I'm always pissy.
我一天到晚都心情不好
我不喜欢和他在一起的自己
I don't like myself when I'm with him.
我已经不喜欢自己了
光是看着他我就受不了
I can't stand to even look at him.
可悲、温吞又带着歉意的笑容
That pathetic, wimpy, apologetic smile.
好像受了伤的猫咪一样
你在干嘛？
What are you doing?
我没在干嘛
I'm not doing anything.
新鲜感已经消失了
The bloom is certainly off the rose at this point.
你在耍我吗？
Are you screwing with me?
没有
no!
你真的在耍我
You are screwing with me.
我没有
I'm not!
你有
You clearly are!
我们…
Let's just take a minute and just...
先冷静一下，暂时…
派屈克，走开 甜心…
Patrick, get the fuck away!
离我远一点!
什么？
Can we talk about it?
能不能谈谈？
no! Get the fuck away!
不行!你给我滚!
乔尔贝里许…
嗨，克蕾婷
Hey, Clementine.
你好
Hey.
很高兴能见到你
nice to see you.
是啊
Yes.
…很有教养
...and she's smart, I think, but not educated.
我觉得她很聪明，可惜没教养
没办法和她聊书的事
I couldn't talk to her about books.
她比较喜欢看杂志
She's more of a magazine-reading girl.
她的字汇有待加强
Her vocabulary leaves something to be desired.
事实上我带她出去很丢脸 你好
The truth is, I was embarrassed in public...
因为她的发音…
because she would pronounce 'library' 'li-berry'.
在发音上很不讲究
你好
“土”书馆
你看我找到什么了
Look what I found.
若克蕾婷有吸引人之处
I think if there's a truly seductive quality about Clementine...
就是她的个性保证不落俗套
it's that her personality promises to take you out of the mundane...
我看起来很瘦
Made me look skinny.
像燃烧的陨石
...amazing, burning meteorite will carry you to another world,
带你到另一个世界
一个充满刺激的世界
where things are exciting.
但你很快就会发现
But what you quickly learn is that it's really an elaborate ruse.
其实那是一个诡计
很抱歉我对你大呼小叫
I'm sorry I yelled at you.
没关系
It's okay.
看得出来很矫揉做作
但还是很吸引人
I really like you.
我很喜欢你，不想对你恶言相向
I hate that I said mean things about you.
我把收音机关掉
Let me turn this off.
这样才公平啊
Hey, that's only fair.
至于她的头发，根本是乱来嘛
The whole thing with the hair, it's all bullshit.
我喜欢你的头发
I really like your hair.
真是太可悲了 谢谢你
Thank you.
我喜欢你的头发 谢谢你
I really like your hair. Thank you.
我是说真的
I do.
这个世界一片混乱 头发还染色，我是说…
你要不要喝杯酒？
You want a drink or something?
有没有威士忌？
Do you have any whiskey?
我觉得她做爱…
I didn't think her sex was motivated.
毫无动机
I saw it clearly the last night we were together.
我昨晚和她做爱时看透了
没挑逗感
It wasn't sexy.
只是…
It was just...sad.
很悲哀
抱歉，我以为还有
Sorry, I thought there was more.
克蕾婷觉得唯有和男人上床
The only way she can get people to like her is to fuck them.
对方才会喜欢她
至少她会当面挑逗男人的性欲
Or at least dangle the possibility of getting fucked in front of them.
她太饥渴了，又没安全感
I think she's so desperate and insecure...
that she'll sooner or later go around fucking everybody.
早晚会和每个男人上床
我不做这种事
I don't do that.
我不觉得你会这样
I wouldn't think that about you.
因为我不是这种人
Because I don't.
我知道
I know.
你那样说很伤我的心
It really hurts me that you said that, because I don't do that.
因为我不是那种人
I'm so sorry.
对不起
我对这一切都很抱歉
I'm sorry about all this.
我要走了，我有点困惑
I'm going to go.
I'm a little confused.
我不想待在这里
I don't really think I can be here.
再见
Bye.
我以为自己够了解她
I really thought I knew her so well. It was nice meeting you.
很高兴能认识你
But I didn't know her at all.
但我一点也不了解她 和她相处了那么久的时间
What a loss to spend that much time with someone...
才发现不了解她，太可惜了
only to find out that she's a stranger.
等一下!
Wait!
怎样？
What?
不知道，就是想叫住你 你想干嘛？
I don't know. Just wait. What do you want, Joel?
先别走，我不知道
I want you to wait for... just a...while.
只是希望你等…
先等…
等一下
好吧
Okay.
真的吗？
Really?
别把我概念化了
I'm not a concept, just a fucked-up girl looking for peace of mind.
我只是想求得心灵平静的坏女孩
我并不完美
I'm not perfect.
我看不出来你有什么缺点 你会发现的
I can't see anything that I don't like about you right now.
现在看不出来 你会发现的
But you will think of things.
你会思考
我会觉得跟着你乏味又不自由
And I'll get bored with you...
因为我就是那种人
and feel trapped, because that's what happens with me.
好吧
Okay.
好吧 好吧
Okay. Okay.
Change your heart
Look around you
It will astound you
Bow, I need your lovin'
Like the sunshine
And everybody's gotta learn sometime
Everybody's gotta learn sometime
Mm-mm-mm
Change your heart
And look aroundyou
It will astoundyou
I needyour lovin'
Like the sunshine
And everybody's gotta learn sometime
Everybody's gotta learn sometime
Mm-mm-mm